http://www.grahamhancock.com/privacy/

Privacy Policy
The privacy policy for the Graham Hancock website as a whole is that any information you give us or that we obtain about you will not be given to any third parties.
We do not, and will not, gather any personal information about you such age, sex, location, etc. without your permission. If we do seek this information, it will be done by questionaire and will be optional.
Surfing the Site
All requests for pages on the website are logged. The information that is logged includes the browser you are using, the type of computer you are using, where you are connecting from and the page you are requesting. All of this information is passed to our server by your web browser. The browser cannot send personal information about you. This information is primarily used to see how busy the site is and which times of the day/week are busiest. In addition we can use this information to decide what functionality we can safely include on the site.
We use cookies to understand and save your preferences for future visits, keep track of advertisements and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.
What personal data we collect and why we collect it
We collect information from you when you subscribe to our newsletter, or register for our messageboards.
Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.
Comments
When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.
An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture may be visible to the public in the context of your comment.
Cookies
If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment.
Google Analytics
Google Analytics lets us analyse how visitors use our site, so that we may improve it and provide a better user experience. These cookies collect data anonymously. Please see Google’s privacy policy for further information.
Phorum
Our messageboard stores cookies to keep track of your account.
YouTube cookies
We embed YouTube videos. YouTube uses cookies to build video statistics and improve their site experience.
Amazon Associates
We are a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated sites.
Embedded content from other websites
Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.
These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.
Analytics
We use Google Analytics which may collect your data. The Google Analytics Privacy Policy may be found here: https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245
How long we retain your data
If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.
For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.
The Message Board
The Message Board uses cookies to store your viewing preferences, eg., flat view, threaded view, and to determine which posts you have already read. It also used to enable the post message form to be partly prefilled. No other information is stored via this cookie.
Mailing List
The hancock-announce mailing list is a subscription only mailing list. Each message to the list includes instructions on how to unsubscribe from the list. The addresses subscribed to the list will not, under any circumstance, be given to any third party.
Definitions
A cookie is a piece of information that a website asks your browser to store on your computer. The website can then request this information back to provide you with a customised page. It is used to link the current surfing session to an earlier one. The ticket you get from a dry-cleaning shop is a perfect mundane example of a cookie; the only thing it’s useful for is to relate a later transaction to this one (so you get the same clothes back).
